

Profile

Experienced group finance manager.

Audit and tax compliance background. Proven track record driving growth and scaling business operations across markets in Central Europe and Southern Africa.

Career Highlights:

Overview:

2014: Achieved a successful restructuring of Albatros South Africa's regional operations.

2015: Expanded Service Level Agreements (SLAs) with key enterprise clients, overseeing +500 hardware interfaces for over +150,000 users across Southern Africa.

2016: Earned a promotion to the position of Group Financial Controller.

2017-2021: Accomplished the successful execution of a 5-year business plan, which involved revamping crucial products, growing technical teams, and localizing regional distribution strategies.

2020: Negotiated a profitable sale of Digital Golf Solutions and boosted distribution revenue through exclusive licensing agreements in the French, Belgian, and Swiss markets.

2021-2022: Collaborated with Marc Fournier of Serena Venture Capital to represent Albatros in numerous negotiations with external investors. Successfully completed all due diligence requirements, resulting in multiple offers.

Led the 100% buyout of the Albatros group by NBC Sports Next, a sports technology division of Comcast/NBCUniversal.

Promoted to Director of 3 of the NBC Sports Next subsidiaries.

Employment History

Contractor (Finance), NBC Sports Next, Karlsruhe

MARCH 2023 - AUGUST 2023

- Prepared monthly, quarterly and annual financial statements in accordance with Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP)
- Provided guidance and training to staff on accounting procedures and best practices
- Developed and maintained an accurate and up-to-date accounting system that tracked against budgeted forecasts

Director of Finance, Albatros Software, Karlsruhe

APRIL 2013 - MARCH 2023

Albatros Software is a SaaS software developer specializing in the golf industry. As part of the senior stakeholders I drove business strategy, financial reporting, budgeting and cash flow management.

- Lead accountants in Germany, France, and South Africa to deliver timely reports and reach critical KPIs
- Liaised with auditors and tax consultants in Germany, France and South Africa to consistently produce clean audits and ad hoc reviews.
- Lead key contract negotiations with customers and suppliers.
- Scaled operations for new Enterprise-, B2B- and B2C solutions.
- Grew revenue through improved distribution and licensing terms.

Details

Abu Dhabi United Arab Emirates Tel: +971 585 623236 eben.johansen@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

South African

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

13 January 1983 Walvis Bay, Namibia

Skills

Financial Accounting

Financial Reporting

Budgeting & Forecasting

Business Strategy

Business Development

Contract Negotiations

+10 years experience in online businesses and SaaS industry

Languages

Afrikaans - Native

English - Native

German - Level A2

Past Projects and Partnerships

www.digme.co.za
www.dgsgolf.com
www.gravityvfx.com

Co-Founder, Digme Solutions (Pty) Ltd, Cape Town

JUNE 2018 - JANUARY 2020

Co-founded DigMe Solutions alongside Grant Joliffe, a virtual accounting and business administration service provider.

Specific services included;

- · Creation of corporate entities
- Business- and tax registrations
- Digital accounting and bookkeeping services
- Monthly payroll solutions
- Basic website design
- Online payment integration
- Micro-financing solutions

Financial Accountant, Platypus Productions (Pty) Ltd, Cape Town, South Africa

APRIL 2011 - MARCH 2013

Platypus Productions is an international television and media production company

- Maintain and report complete, accurate, up-to-date accounting and tax records
- Gained experience working with large international brands, including Vodafone, Sports-Illustrated, Isuzu, Anheuser-Busch InBev and others

Audit Senior, PKF Chartered Accountants and Auditors, Cape Town, South Africa

JULY 2007 - MARCH 2011

- Successfully supervised and completed audits within budget and on time, for publicly traded- and large private corporations.
- Gained valuable exposure to a variety of industries, including; International Commercial and Residential Property Developers, Investment Funds, Investment Fund Administrators, Mining, Health-Care, Government Agencies, Software Development, Telecommunications and Broadcasting corporations
- Presented audit findings to clients and made meaningful recommendations and improvements to accounting processes and financial controls
- Prepared Annual and Interim Financial Statements in accordance with IFRS and South African Tax regulations
- Assess the professional development of junior auditors enrolled in the SAICA training programme

Audit Clerk, Alliott Andersen Nell Incorporated, Cape Town, South Africa

FEBRUARY 2006 - JUNE 2007

Enrolled in the SAICA training programme through then, Alliott Andersen Nell Incorporated, today operating as PKF Constantiaberg.

- Performed financial audits and agreed-upon procedures for small private entities, family trusts and body corporates
- Gained exposure to companies in the Property Development, Law Firms, Food & Beverage, and small manufacturing industries

Education

Foundations: Data Analytics, Google Certification, Abu Dhabi

JULY 2023 - AUGUST 2023

Diploma in Management Accounting, Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA), United Kingdom

SEPTEMBER 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Finance in a Digital Environment, Financial Reporting, Management Accounting

Certificate in Accounting and Business Management, Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA), United Kingdom

Ethics, Corporate Governance, Business Law, Financial Accounting, Management Accounting and Business Economics

Incomplete - Bachelor of Commerce (BCompt), University of South Africa (UNISA), Cape Town - South Africa

FEBRUARY 2006 - AUGUST 2019

29 of 29 Modules Completed | Finalized all modules in 2012. Was not awarded degree due to the expiration of historical credits gained through the University of Stellenbosch. Completed all expired modules between 2017 and 2019. Was not awarded degree due to course curriculum changes in 2019

Incomplete - Bachelor of Commerce and Law, University of Stellenbosch (USB), Stellenbosch - South Africa

FEBRUARY 2002 - DECEMBER 2005

14 of 19 Subjects Completed | Law degree specializing in South African Mercantile-, Private- and Public Law, including Insurance Regulations, Accounting, Economics, Statistics and Business Management.

Grade 12 (GCSE - International), Walvis Bay High School, Walvis Bay - Namibia

JANUARY 1997 - DECEMBER 2001

B+ overall grade avg.

3 distinctions in Economics, Business Studies, and Accounting

Other subjects included Afrikaans, English and Mathematics

References

Volker Schorp | VP Product & Technology from NBC Sports Next schorp@albatros.net | https://www.albatros.net

Marc Fournier | Managing Partner from Serena Venture Capital mfournier@serena.vc | https://www.serena.vc

Grant Joliffe | Co-Founder from DigMe Solutions

grant@digme.co.za | https://www.digme.co.za